Ever since I was young, I loved to read.
My favorite book was The Adventures of Niké.
It contained records of the witch, Niké,
as she traveled around the world.
I want to go to lots of places like Niké!
Then first, you need to study
to become a witch like Niké.
If I become a witch, then you'll let me travel?
Of course. Right?
Huh?
Yeah...
Only once you're older and become a witch, okay?
Really?
Really really?
Really really.
I'm going to be a witch!
I don't mean to brag,
but I worked assiduously,
studying fervently, day after day.
And then...
There was a girl who passed
the magic exams at age 14--
the youngest in the history of
the Peaceful Country of Robetta--
and she became an apprentice witch.
That's right, it was me.
"Elaina, the Apprentice Witch"
Congrats on passing your magic exams, Elaina.
We're so proud of you.
What's wrong? You're not happy?
The other examinees were so weak...
At this rate, it's only a matter of time
before I become a full witch, huh?
Oh?
Oh, my...
In order for an apprentice witch
to become a full witch,
she must study under another witch
and have her acknowledge her abilities.
Coming!
Yes, what is it?
U-Um, I'm Elaina, and I just passed the magi--
Coming!
Oh, you're...
I just passed the magic exams and--
However, it seemed the witches
of this country did not find it amusing
that I was the youngest to
ever pass the magic exams...
I can't do it! I'm sorry!
...and they all refused my
request to be their apprentice.
At this rate, I won't be able to become a witch.
What should I do...?
It seems a suspicious witch has
settled down deep in the woods.
I heard those rumors, too.
Apparently, she's called the Stardust Witch.
I went to go meet this "Stardust Witch."
I thought that if she didn't know who I was,
then maybe she'd take me on as an apprentice.
Is that it?
Now, now...
The Stardust Witch...?
There, there!
Maybe I'll go home...
There!
Oh, good, good!
Yup, yup!
There, there!
Oh, oh, yay!
Um, excuse me...
Oh? What's this?
Could you be Miss Elaina?
You know who I am?
Yes. You're the girl who passed
the magic exams easily at 14, right?
You're famous, for better or for worse.
Well, did you need something?
No. Sorry to bother you.
Are you here to ask about
becoming my apprentice?
In that case--
You're going to say no, anyway, right?
It's fine.
Huh?!
I've got time, anyway.
But... um, me...?
I'm not the same as the Robetta witches.
It doesn't matter what
kind of girl you are to me.
Please let me be your apprentice!
This is how I met the Stardust
Witch--my teacher, Miss Fran.
Good morning!
Good morning...
I'm hungry. Please make something to eat.
What would you like?
Let's see...
I feel like steak.
Isn't that kind of heavy for breakfast?
Then, some of those weeds over there will do.
Aren't you giving up a little too much?
Then, bread will be fine!
I'm going to go pick some wild vegetables.
Um, Miss Fran, I'd like you
to teach me some magic...
We'll do that later. I'm off!
See you later...
No matter how many days passed,
Miss Fran wouldn't teach me at all.
Elaina, we're out of food.
Please go buy some from the town.
Yes, ma'am.
Elaina, please catch about five geckos.
I need them for my research.
Yes, ma'am.
Elaina, is dinner ready yet?
Yes, ma'am!
How to make painkillers...
Let's see...
Elaina, there's a spider in the bath.
Please get rid of it. It's scary...
Yes, ma'am.
It's mixed in, huh...?
You don't like mushrooms?
Witches should not be picky eaters.
Elaina, please massage my shoulders.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, that feels good.
Why won't you teach me any magic?
Oh, harder!
With this and that, a month passed
without her teaching me anything.
I've just been doing chores
ever since coming here.
What am I doing?
Do you finally feel like teaching me magic?
No, there's nothing for me to teach you.
I see.
Also, I don't feel like stew today.
Please make something else.
Very well.
This seems to be a good time...
Elaina.
Yes?
We'll have a test now.
Huh?
Miss Fran, what kind of test is this?
I'll have you fight against me.
You're kidding... right?
Okay, let's start.
Huh?!
If that's what you want,
then I'll send you flying!
Is she trying to kill me?
What's the matter?
You overwhelmed everyone at the magic exams.
Is that all you've got?
Let me have some more fun.
Oh my, finished already?
Even though you're a star student,
you're nothing to write home about...
I-I'm sorry!
I didn't think you'd start crying...
Um... Let's see...
Take a look at this!
Here are some of those butterflies you love!
I'm not the one who likes butterflies!
Th-Then...
Look, a crown made of weeds!
I don't need that!
Then...
Look, how about this?
There, there--hot, hot! It's too hot!
Um, in that case...
Calm down.
Please, stop!
What are you trying to do?
I'm sorry, really.
It looks like I overdid it a little.
Please stop messing around!
You were having fun teasing me!
I wasn't having fun at all...
You were never planning on making me a witch!
I hate you!
I hate you all!
Even though I believed in you
and endured everything...
I believed that everything would work out...
But you're just the same
as those Robetta witches!
I trusted you.
You have no idea how hard I was working!
I just... wanted you to acknowledge me...
I really am sorry.
I knew very well how you truly felt.
You did a good job to endure it for so long.
Are you trying to trick me again?
No, I won't trick you anymore.
I'm at my limit, too.
You know, I was doing all this
because your parents asked me to.
What?
If she keeps going like this
and becomes an adult,
there might come a day
when she's unable to recover...
That's why you want me
to take her as my apprentice
and teach her about failures and setbacks?
Yes...
But...
Of course, we aren't asking you
to do this for free, Miss Fran.
Oh, dear! I'm not a witch
who can be enticed by money...
I grudgingly accepted your parents' request.
At first, I thought I'd put you
through extraordinary trials
so that you would learn about setbacks.
But you never balked at working hard
in order to achieve your goal,
you're talented,
and you understand very well how people see you.
I thought it wouldn't do
any good to give you trials
because you would just
endure them and rise again.
But...
...that's also your main problem.
You endure too much, Elaina.
Please don't feel like all you
have to do is bear with everything.
If there's something you don't like, fight it.
Be able to clearly say "No" when you need to.
So you can protect yourself.
Then... the reason you wouldn't
teach me magic this whole time...
I was waiting for you to reach your limit.
It took a whole month!
Today's test was for the same reason.
I really am sorry.
Don't endure.
That was the first time I'd ever been told that.
Miss Fran...
You have skill and talent.
All you're lacking is experience.
My real training started on that day.
In order to gain a lot
of different experiences...
Good morning, Miss Fran.
Good morning, Elaina.
I'm hungry, so please make something to eat.
Here are some weeds.
Um, what kind of harassment is this?
You told me to stop enduring things,
so I tried to be honest about my feeling
like making food for you was a pain.
Just kidding.
Is yesterday's leftover stew
and some hard bread okay?
It is, right?
Yes.
In the days after that--
The days when I trained with Miss Fran--
Sometimes, they were hard...
...but they were very fulfilling and fun.
You've become strong. Very strong.
It's my first time beating you.
With this, you're training's over.
Huh?
You worked hard this past year.
I don't have anything else to teach you.
Congratulations, Elaina.
The Stardust Witch officially
acknowledges you as a witch.
Thank you very much.
By the way, about your witch title...
How about "the Ashen Witch"?
How did you come up with it?
Your hair is the color of ash.
Don't you think that's a little too simplistic?
I thought it was pretty cool, though...
By the way, why are you
called "the Stardust Witch"?
Because it's cool, of course!
Well? What do you think about "the Ashen Witch"?
It's fine.
It's decided then.
Ashen Witch, Elaina.
Please do your best from now on.
Yes, ma'am.
Well then, I'm off.
Where?
Miss Fran told me then
that she was actually a distinguished
witch from another country.
Then, why did you come here?
There was someone I wanted to meet.
Someone you wanted to meet?
Did you meet them?
I wish I could stay longer,
but there are many people
waiting for me back home.
Goodbye, Elaina.
Let's meet again someday.
Yes, ma'am!
Goodbye, Miss Fran!
Father, Mother, I've become a witch.
So please allow me to go on a journey.
You don't have to rush things, do you?
You're serious, aren't you?
Of course.
Then, go.
I will.
However, there are three promises you must keep.
First, if you are in trouble, run away.
Second, don't think of
yourself as anyone special.
Don't forget that you're
the same as everyone else.
And third, make sure you come back one day
and show us that you're doing well.
Can you keep these promises?
Yes!
A-Are you really leaving...?
It's something she decided for herself.
Let's see her off properly, okay?
Dear, you seem like you'll die
of shock when Elaina gets married...
It looks good on you.
Isn't it a little plain?
That's exactly right for a traveler.
Take this, too, just in case.
It's the same as what I'm wearing, right?
It's just in case the wind blows it away.
A spare?
A spare.
Then, I'll bring it with me.
Also--
A diary?
Write a diary of your travels like Niké.
Let me hear your story
when you come back someday.
Okay, I'll bring it with me, too.
Please look forward to hearing the
story of the journey of the Ashen Witch.
I will.
Have a good trip, Elaina.
I will!
And so, I set off on my journey.
As the wind blows, as my fancy led me,
I traveled here and there
and experienced many things,
and three years passed.
Now, here's a question:
Who is the witch so
beautiful she'd make you sigh
flying through the stark mountain range?
That's right--
It's me, age 18.